{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": ".......... is not part of the status bar",
      "options": [
        "a. page number",
        "b. line",
        "c. column",
        "d. section",
        "e. drop cap"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. drop cap",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Convert 10610 to base 2",
      "options": [
        "a. 01010112",
        "b. 1101012",
        "c. 1010102",
        "d. 011010102",
        "e. 010110102"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. 010110102",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Hierarchical model, network model and relational model are all parts of",
      "options": [
        "a. system model",
        "b. network model",
        "c. database model",
        "d. data structure",
        "e. data architecture"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. database model",
      "id": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The Drag and Drop feature can be turn on or off in the Tools command",
      "options": [
        "a. false",
        "b. true",
        "c. not correct",
        "d. not true",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. true",
      "id": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "The control buttons on the title bar include all except",
      "options": [
        "a. restore",
        "b. minimise",
        "c. maximise",
        "d. close",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. none of the above",
      "id": 5
    },
    {
      "question": "----------- provides a list of toggle options",
      "options": [
        "a. list boxes",
        "b. text boxes",
        "c. check boxes",
        "d. option button",
        "e. drop down list"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. check boxes",
      "id": 6
    },
    {
      "question": "The F4 command in DOS will",
      "options": [
        "a. redisplay buffer",
        "b. delete all",
        "c. delete all characters in buffer to the last command",
        "d. redisplay all characters",
        "e. do nothing"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. delete all characters in buffer to the last command",
      "id": 7
    },
    {
      "question": "The area that first appear on the screen after the system boots is",
      "options": [
        "a. wallpaper",
        "b. screen saver",
        "c. background",
        "d. desktop",
        "e. windows OS"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. desktop",
      "id": 8
    },
    {
      "question": "Convert 111101012 to base 8",
      "options": [
        "a. 1748",
        "b. 7128",
        "c. 7218",
        "d. 2718",
        "e. 1728"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. 1728",
      "id": 9
    },
    {
      "question": "The formula for subtraction in Excel is",
      "options": [
        "a. no minus in excel",
        "b. =A4-B4",
        "c. =SUBTRACT(A4:B4)",
        "d. =(A4-B4)SUBTRACT",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. =A4-B4",
      "id": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "The splitting of text to fit in a cell is called",
      "options": [
        "a. word wrap",
        "b. insertion point",
        "c. text wrap",
        "d. name boxing",
        "e. auto fill"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. word wrap",
      "id": 11
    },
    {
      "question": "The command VOL in command prompt is",
      "options": [
        "a. increase the system volume",
        "b. display a disk volume label and serial number",
        "c. display the disk volume level",
        "d. display all files in the volume",
        "e. display nothing"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. display a disk volume label and serial number",
      "id": 12
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick the odd one out",
      "options": [
        "a. drawing toolbar",
        "b. status bar",
        "c. formula bar",
        "d. formatting toolbar",
        "e. standard tool"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. standard tool",
      "id": 13
    },
    {
      "question": "Advantage of electronic data processing is",
      "options": [
        "a. faster processing speed",
        "b. automatic data processing as it enters the system",
        "c. accurate data output",
        "d. timely availability of result",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
      "id": 14
    },
    {
      "question": "Games, web browsers, and application programs are written in",
      "options": [
        "a. low-level language",
        "b. high-level language",
        "c. computer software translators",
        "d. binary codes",
        "e. Computer compilers"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. high-level language",
      "id": 15
    },
    {
      "question": "A machine language is in 0 and 1",
      "options": [
        "a. true",
        "b. false",
        "c. ASCII language",
        "d. all of the above",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. true",
      "id": 16
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is not part of a standard keyboard",
      "options": [
        "a. numeric keys",
        "b. alphanumeric keys",
        "c. text keys",
        "d. function keys",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. text keys",
      "id": 17
    },
    {
      "question": "Deleting the original item does not automatically delete the shortcut",
      "options": [
        "a. true",
        "b. false",
        "c. not true",
        "d. probably",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. true",
      "id": 18
    },
    {
      "question": "The data capture technique best suitable for examinations and questionnaires is",
      "options": [
        "a. optical character recognition",
        "b. magnetic character recognition",
        "c. mark sensing device",
        "d. Kimball tags",
        "e. magnetic tags"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. mark sensing device",
      "id": 19
    },
    {
      "question": "The processing of data by consisting of a keyboard actuated by a machine operator is called",
      "options": [
        "a. electronic data processing",
        "b. manual data processing",
        "c. human data processing",
        "d. machine data processing",
        "e. mechanical data processing"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. mechanical data processing",
      "id": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "file handler, formatter, and sort/list utility are all examples of",
      "options": [
        "a. translators",
        "b. applications",
        "c. OS",
        "d. utilities",
        "e. computer tools"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. utilities",
      "id": 21
    },
    {
      "question": "Classification of computers by types includes",
      "options": [
        "a. microcomputer and minicomputer",
        "b. digital and analog computer",
        "c. special and general computer",
        "d. mainframe and supercomputer",
        "e. wearable and special computers"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. microcomputer and minicomputer",
      "id": 22
    },
    {
      "question": "--------------- is not a feature of an operating system",
      "options": [
        "a. sharing",
        "b. long term storage",
        "c. efficiency",
        "d. redundancy",
        "e. reliability"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. redundancy",
      "id": 23
    },
    {
      "question": "The keyboard command to close a window is",
      "options": [
        "a. CTRL + X",
        "b. CTRL + W",
        "c. CTRL + Y",
        "d. CTRL + SHIFT + DELETE",
        "e. CTRL + END"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. CTRL + W",
      "id": 24
    },
    {
      "question": "The move through a cell is achieved through",
      "options": [
        "a. use of the arrow keys",
        "b. selecting with the mouse",
        "c. use of the tab key",
        "d. a, b and c are correct",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. a, b and c are correct",
      "id": 25
    },
    {
      "question": "The formula bar in excel display",
      "options": [
        "a. the content of an active cell",
        "b. the formula in a cell",
        "c. the name of the active cell",
        "d. a and b is correct",
        "e. a, b, c are correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. a, b, c are correct",
      "id": 26
    },
    {
      "question": "A temporary storage area in computer memory is called",
      "options": [
        "a. RAM",
        "b. ROM",
        "c. primary memory",
        "d. secondary storage",
        "e. buffer"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. buffer",
      "id": 27
    },
    {
      "question": "What formula should be used to add the values in cells A2 and A4?",
      "options": [
        "a. =Sum (A1:A3)",
        "b. Sum (A2:A4)",
        "c. =SUM(A2;A4)",
        "d. =A1:A3",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Sum (A2:A4)",
      "id": 28
    },
    {
      "question": "The command dir t*.* will",
      "options": [
        "a. display s*.* is not an internal or external command",
        "b. display an error message",
        "c. display all dir and files that start with letter t",
        "d. display t*.* is a file",
        "e. display t*.* does not exist"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. display all dir and files that start with letter t",
      "id": 29
    },
    {
      "question": "The cls command in DOS",
      "options": [
        "a. increase the system volume",
        "b. display a disk volume label and serial number",
        "c. display the disk volume level",
        "d. display all files in the volume",
        "e. display nothing"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. clear the screen",
      "id": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "The roller on a PS2 mouse enables the user to",
      "options": [
        "a. scroll up and down",
        "b. saves 35% of the time spent scrolling a document",
        "c. zoom in and out a graphic application",
        "d. a, b and c is correct",
        "e. only b and c is correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. a, b and c is correct",
      "id": 31
    },
    {
      "question": "Triple click on a mouse selects",
      "options": [
        "a. a text",
        "b. a line or paragraph",
        "c. a word",
        "d. all",
        "e. a letter"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. a line or paragraph",
      "id": 32
    },
    {
      "question": "To expand the length of a column",
      "options": [
        "a. move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "b. move the mouse pointer to the line between the rows, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "c. move the mouse pointer away from the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "d. move the mouse pointer to the line away from columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "e. none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
      "id": 33
    },
    {
      "question": "The pick tool in CorelDraw is used to",
      "options": [
        "a. cut an image",
        "b. move an image",
        "c. resize an image",
        "d. rotate an image",
        "e. reshape an image"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. move an image",
      "id": 34
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a programming language",
      "options": [
        "a. Python",
        "b. Java",
        "c. HTML",
        "d. C++",
        "e. COBOL"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. HTML",
      "id": 35
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of CPU",
      "options": [
        "a. Computer Processing Unit",
        "b. Central Processing Unit",
        "c. Central Printed Unit",
        "d. Computer Printed Unit",
        "e. Central Processor Unit"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Central Processing Unit",
      "id": 36
    },
    {
      "question": "In Microsoft Excel, the intersection of a column and row is called",
      "options": [
        "a. cell",
        "b. box",
        "c. slot",
        "d. grid",
        "e. spreadsheet"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. cell",
      "id": 37
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the INDEX function in Excel",
      "options": [
        "a. To return the relative position of an item in a range",
        "b. To create an index for the worksheet",
        "c. To return the average value in a range",
        "d. To identify the maximum value in a range",
        "e. To count the number of cells in a range"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. To return the relative position of an item in a range",
      "id": 38
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of computer memory",
      "options": [
        "a. RAM",
        "b. ROM",
        "c. Cache",
        "d. CPU",
        "e. Virtual Memory"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. CPU",
      "id": 39
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the acronym HTML stand for",
      "options": [
        "a. Hyperlink and Text Markup Language",
        "b. HyperText Markup Language",
        "c. High-Level Text Management Language",
        "d. Hyperlink and Table Markup Language",
        "e. High-Level Table Management Language"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. HyperText Markup Language",
      "id": 40
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a web browser",
      "options": [
        "a. Chrome",
        "b. Firefox",
        "c. Safari",
        "d. Python",
        "e. Edge"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Python",
      "id": 41
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a firewall",
      "options": [
        "a. To protect against viruses",
        "b. To filter network traffic",
        "c. To enhance internet speed",
        "d. To improve computer performance",
        "e. To create a secure Wi-Fi connection"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. To filter network traffic",
      "id": 42
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is known as the 'mother of all languages'",
      "options": [
        "a. Python",
        "b. Java",
        "c. C++",
        "d. Assembly Language",
        "e. COBOL"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Assembly Language",
      "id": 43
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the acronym URL stand for",
      "options": [
        "a. Uniform Resource Locator",
        "b. Universal Resource Locator",
        "c. Unified Resource Locator",
        "d. Unique Resource Locator",
        "e. User-friendly Resource Locator"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Uniform Resource Locator",
      "id": 44
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a data structure",
      "options": [
        "a. Algorithm",
        "b. Variable",
        "c. Pointer",
        "d. Array",
        "e. Operator"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Array",
      "id": 45
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the command 'chmod' in Unix-based operating systems",
      "options": [
        "a. Change mode of a file or directory",
        "b. Change motherboard settings",
        "c. Change computer hostname",
        "d. Change display resolution",
        "e. Change network configuration"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Change mode of a file or directory",
      "id": 46
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary function of the CPU",
      "options": [
        "a. Store data permanently",
        "b. Execute instructions",
        "c. Manage network connections",
        "d. Create graphics",
        "e. Control input devices"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Execute instructions",
      "id": 47
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a relational database management system",
      "options": [
        "a. MongoDB",
        "b. MySQL",
        "c. Redis",
        "d. Cassandra",
        "e. CouchDB"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. MySQL",
      "id": 48
    },
    {
      "question": "What does LAN stand for",
      "options": [
        "a. Local Area Network",
        "b. Large Area Network",
        "c. Linked Access Network",
        "d. Longitudinal Array Network",
        "e. Low-latency Audio Network"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Local Area Network",
      "id": 49
    },
    {
      "question": "In programming, what does the acronym API stand for",
      "options": [
        "a. Application Programming Interface",
        "b. Advanced Programming Interface",
        "c. Automated Programming Interface",
        "d. Array Programming Interface",
        "e. Algorithmic Programming Interface"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Application Programming Interface",
      "id": 50
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of DNS in computer networks",
      "options": [
        "a. Direct Network Security",
        "b. Domain Name System",
        "c. Data Network Services",
        "d. Digital Network Storage",
        "e. Dynamic Network Solutions"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Domain Name System",
      "id": 51
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is often used for artificial intelligence",
      "options": [
        "a. Java",
        "b. Python",
        "c. C++",
        "d. Ruby",
        "e. PHP"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Python",
      "id": 52
    },
    {
      "question": "Optic coaxial cable is to local area network as micro wave is to",
      "options": [
        "a. LAN",
        "b. WAN",
        "c. GAN",
        "d. Large Area Network",
        "e. Wide Aperture Network"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Large Area Network",
      "id": 53
    },
    {
      "question": "The use of very large scale integrated circuits is common in",
      "options": [
        "a. Fourth Generation Computers",
        "b. Third Generation Computers",
        "c. Second Generation Computers",
        "d. First Generation Computers",
        "e. Fifth Generation Computers"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Fourth Generation Computers",
      "id": 54
    },
    {
      "question": "The main purpose of storing data is for",
      "options": [
        "a. Creating a database",
        "b. Processing",
        "c. Data Usage",
        "d. None of the above",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
      "id": 55
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a common use of the internet",
      "options": [
        "a. File Sharing",
        "b. Voice Telephony",
        "c. Electronic Fund Transfer",
        "d. Electronic Mail",
        "e. Manual Filing"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. Manual Filing",
      "id": 56
    },
    {
      "question": "The first page a user logged on to is called",
      "options": [
        "a. Welcome Page",
        "b. Web Site",
        "c. Internet Page",
        "d. Home Page",
        "e. Web Page"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Home Page",
      "id": 57
    },
    {
      "question": "The total number of columns in Microsoft Office Excel 2003 is",
      "options": [
        "a. 18834",
        "b. 18845",
        "c. 168435",
        "d. 164853",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. None of the above",
      "id": 58
    },
    {
      "question": "The work area in Microsoft Word is known as",
      "options": [
        "a. Document Area",
        "b. Work Space",
        "c. Document Space",
        "d. Space Area",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Document Area",
      "id": 59
    },
    {
      "question": "The maximum number of worksheets in a workbook is",
      "options": [
        "a. 257",
        "b. 256",
        "c. 266",
        "d. 265",
        "e. 267"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. 256",
      "id": 60
    },
    {
      "question": "Common domain names include",
      "options": [
        "a. .com",
        "b. .edu",
        "c. .gov",
        "d. .org",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
      "id": 61
    },
    {
      "question": "The right button on the mouse is used to",
      "options": [
        "a. Execute a command",
        "b. Call for options",
        "c. Open an application",
        "d. Format a document",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
      "id": 62
    },
    {
      "question": "Charts are used to view data in Microsoft Office Excel",
      "options": [
        "a. False",
        "b. True",
        "c. Not True",
        "d. All of the above",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. True",
      "id": 63
    },
    {
      "question": "The Fill Handle is used to generate a formula sequence to adjacent cells",
      "options": [
        "a. True",
        "b. False",
        "c. All of the above",
        "d. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. True",
      "id": 64
    },
    {
      "question": "The AutoText feature of Microsoft Word helps in the automatic insertion of images",
      "options": [
        "a. True",
        "b. False",
        "c. Not of the above",
        "d. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. False",
      "id": 65
    },
    {
      "question": "Procedure-oriented languages are common to",
      "options": [
        "a. High-Level Language",
        "b. Low-Level Language",
        "c. Foreign Language",
        "d. List Logic Processing Language",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. High-Level Language",
      "id": 66
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a data element of a database",
      "options": [
        "a. Field",
        "b. File",
        "c. Records",
        "d. Character",
        "e. Directory"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. Directory",
      "id": 67
    },
    {
      "question": "Database architecture can be viewed in respect to the organization of data",
      "options": [
        "a. Not True",
        "b. Not Entirely True",
        "c. True",
        "d. False",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. True",
      "id": 68
    },
    {
      "question": "Commercial facilities of WAN include",
      "options": [
        "a. E-Governance",
        "b. Viewdata",
        "c. E-Banking",
        "d. E-Solutions",
        "e. E-Travel"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Viewdata",
      "id": 69
    },
    {
      "question": "CTRL+ALT+DELETE will perform what action",
      "options": [
        "a. Shutdown the system",
        "b. Calls up the task manager",
        "c. Restart the system",
        "d. B and C are correct",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. B and C are correct",
      "id": 70
    },
    {
      "question": "FTP is an acronym for",
      "options": [
        "a. File Translate Process",
        "b. File Transfer Process",
        "c. File Transfer Protocol",
        "d. File Translate Protocol",
        "e. File Transfer Partition"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. File Transfer Process",
      "id": 71
    },
    {
      "question": "... is not a file extension name",
      "options": [
        "a. .cdr",
        "b. .doc",
        "c. .ppt",
        "d. .bas",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. None of the above",
      "id": 72
    },
    {
      "question": "The EXIT command in DOS command prompt will",
      "options": [
        "a. Display all dir folders",
        "b. Shut down the computer",
        "c. Close the command prompt window",
        "d. Not do anything",
        "e. Restart the computer"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. Close the command prompt window",
      "id": 73
    },
    {
      "question": "The movement of the cursor to the next line as it gets to the end of the margin in the document area is called",
      "options": [
        "a. Cursor Movement",
        "b. Word Wrap",
        "c. Text Wrap",
        "d. Enter New Line",
        "e. Neither A, B, C nor D"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Word Wrap",
      "id": 74
    },
    {
      "question": "The following are internal or external operable commands in DOS except",
      "options": [
        "a. DEL, COPY, PRINT",
        "b. VERIFY, FORMAT, SHUTDOWN",
        "c. CONVERT, RMDIR, REPLACE",
        "d. COPY, EDIT, PASTE",
        "e. CLS, DIR, ECHO"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. COPY, EDIT, PASTE",
      "id": 75
    },
    {
      "question": "Multiple windows that are opened are indicated on the",
      "options": [
        "a. Menu Bar",
        "b. Standard Tools Bar",
        "c. Notification Bar",
        "d. Task Pane",
        "e. Task Bar"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Task Pane",
      "id": 76
    },
    {
      "question": "A list of logically arranged commands is displayed as",
      "options": [
        "a. Menu Bar",
        "b. Tools Bar",
        "c. Command Bar",
        "d. Standard Tools Bar",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Menu Bar",
      "id": 77
    },
    {
      "question": "A file in Microsoft Office Excel is saved as a",
      "options": [
        "a. Spreadsheet",
        "b. Excel File Doc.",
        "c. Workbook",
        "d. Spread Sheet Book",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. Workbook",
      "id": 78
    },
    {
      "question": "The keyboard command to find a text in a document is",
      "options": [
        "a. Ctrl + A",
        "b. Ctrl + F",
        "c. Ctrl + G",
        "d. Ctrl + H",
        "e. Ctrl + V"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Ctrl + F",
      "id": 79
    },
    {
      "question": "The screen of Microsoft Word is made up of the following components, except:",
      "options": [
        "a. Title Bar",
        "b. Menu Bar",
        "c. Standard Toolbar",
        "d. Formatting Toolbar",
        "e. Page Setup Bar"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. Page Setup Bar",
      "id": 80
    },
    {
      "question": "The movement of the full or part of the document from one place to another, leaving the original copy is called...",
      "options": [
        "a. Cutting",
        "b. Copying",
        "c. Pasting",
        "d. Editing",
        "e. All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Copying",
      "id": 81
    },
    {
      "question": "The function of the Shift + F2 key is",
      "options": [
        "a. Do nothing",
        "b. Copy Text",
        "c. Edit Page",
        "d. Paste All",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Copy Text",
      "id": 82
    },
    {
      "question": "The keyboard key that deletes all the characters in a buffer up to the last character is",
      "options": [
        "a. F4",
        "b. F2",
        "c. F6",
        "d. F8",
        "e. F12"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. F4",
      "id": 83
    },
    {
      "question": "A temporary storage area in computer memory is called",
      "options": [
        "a. RAM",
        "b. ROM",
        "c. Primary Memory",
        "d. Buffer",
        "e. Butter"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. Buffer",
      "id": 84
    },
    {
      "question": "The maximum number of sheets in a workbook is",
      "options": [
        "a. 256",
        "b. 255",
        "c. 265",
        "d. 266",
        "e. 258"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. 256",
      "id": 85
    },
    {
      "question": "What formula should be used to add the values in cells A2 and A4?",
      "options": [
        "a. =Sum (A1:A3)",
        "b. Sum (A2:A4)",
        "c. =A1:A3",
        "d. None of the above",
        "e. =SUM(A2;A4)"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Sum (A2:A4)",
      "id": 86
    },
    {
      "question": "Excel is an electronic spreadsheet to calculate, analyze and view data",
      "options": [
        "a. Very true",
        "b. Not all through",
        "c. Not absolutely true",
        "d. Very wrong",
        "e. False"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Very true",
      "id": 87
    },
    {
      "question": "Moving between cells is achieved through",
      "options": [
        "a. Press the Tab key on the keyboard",
        "b. Use the mouse to select the next cell",
        "c. Use any of the four arrow keys",
        "d. None of the above",
        "e. All of the above except d"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. All of the above except d",
      "id": 88
    },
    {
      "question": "The formula =MAX(c2,d3,f5,g5) will",
      "options": [
        "a. Do nothing",
        "b. Find the sum of the cells",
        "c. Find the maximum of the cells",
        "d. Find the mean of the cells",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. Find the maximum of the cells",
      "id": 89
    },
    {
      "question": "The Fill Handle is to",
      "options": [
        "a. Fill data into a row or column",
        "b. Generate the sequence data in a row or column",
        "c. A and B is correct",
        "d. Only A is correct",
        "e. Only B is correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. A and B is correct",
      "id": 90
    },
    {
      "question": "Font, font style, double strike through, emboss, subscript and all cap are all checkboxes in",
      "options": [
        "a. Edit",
        "b. View",
        "c. File",
        "d. Menu",
        "e. Format"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. Format",
      "id": 91
    },
    {
      "question": "The file with the following extensions .DOC, .VBP, .XLS, and .FOR are",
      "options": [
        "a. Word document, Visual Processor, Excel, Fortran",
        "b. Word document, Visual Basic Program, Excel and Fortran",
        "c. Word document, Visual Basic Package, Excel and Fortran",
        "d. All of the above",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Word document, Visual Basic Program, Excel and Fortran",
      "id": 92
    },
    {
      "question": "Ctrl + U will perform what function on selected text",
      "options": [
        "a. Select All",
        "b. Underline",
        "c. Paste",
        "d. Cut",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. Underline",
      "id": 93
    },
    {
      "question": "The command dir s*.* will",
      "options": [
        "a. Display s*.* is not an internal or external command",
        "b. Display an error message",
        "c. Display all dir and files that start with the letter s",
        "d. Display s*.* is a file",
        "e. Display s*.* does not exist"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. Display all dir and files that start with the letter s",
      "id": 94
    },
    {
      "question": "The cls command in DOS",
      "options": [
        "a. Shutdown the computer",
        "b. Shutdown the system",
        "c. Display all directory with cls name",
        "d. Restart the program",
        "e. Clear the screen"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "e. Clear the screen",
      "id": 95
    },
    {
      "question": "Formatting in Microsoft Excel and Microsoft Word is the same method",
      "options": [
        "a. True",
        "b. Not true",
        "c. False",
        "d. B and C are correct",
        "e. Very false"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. True",
      "id": 96
    },
    {
      "question": "The formula bar in Excel displays",
      "options": [
        "a. The data in an active cell",
        "b. The cell that is selected",
        "c. A and B is correct",
        "d. Only A is correct",
        "e. Only B is correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. A and B is correct",
      "id": 97
    },
    {
      "question": "Ctrl + Z command will perform what function",
      "options": [
        "a. Select All",
        "b. Copy All",
        "c. Undo the last command",
        "d. Display all zip files",
        "e. Show zip folder"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "c. Undo the last command",
      "id": 98
    },
    {
      "question": "Icons are",
      "options": [
        "a. Shortcuts to programs in the computer",
        "b. Picture commands",
        "c. Pictorial representations of programs, applications, and commands",
        "d. All of the above",
        "e. Only D and A are correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
      "id": 99
    },
    {
      "question": "The roller on a PS2 mouse enables the user to",
      "options": [
        "a. Scroll up and down",
        "b. Saves 35% of the time spent scrolling a document",
        "c. Zoom in and out a graphic application",
        "d. A, B and C is correct",
        "e. Only B and C is correct"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "d. A, B and C is correct",
      "id": 100
    },
    {
      "question": "Triple click on a mouse selects",
      "options": [
        "a. A text",
        "b. A line or paragraph",
        "c. A word",
        "d. All",
        "e. A letter"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "b. A line or paragraph",
      "id": 101
    },
    {
      "question": "To expand the length of a column",
      "options": [
        "a. Move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "b. Move the mouse pointer to the line between the rows, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "c. Move the mouse pointer away from the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "d. Move the mouse pointer to the line away from columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
        "e. None of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "a. Move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions",
      "id": 102
    }
  ]
}